Submarines
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Submarines, 2.1.3.1.3.1
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - family photos, circa 1880s - 1930s; 1 (Box 1512)
    - Val with parents. Valentiner (cabinet card), 1
    - Verso: Val with parents. Valentiner, 1-verso
    - Max Valentiner at 1 yrs (cabinet card), 2
    - Verso: Max Valentiner at 1 yrs, 2-verso
    - Max in August 1883? (cabinet card), 3
    - Verso: Max in August 1883? Valentiner, 3-verso
    - View [?] his first sailor suit. (cabinet card), 4
    - Verso: View [?] his first sailor suit. Velentiner Max, 4-verso
    - Johanna the servant girl. [more illegible] (cabinet card), 5
    - Verso: Johanna the servant girl. [more illegible] Return to Valentiner, 5-verso
    - [no description] (cabinet card), 6
    - Valentiner's father, 7
    - Verso: Valentiner's father. Return to Valentiner, 7-verso
    - Valentiners children, 8
    - Verso: Valentiners children, 8-verso
    - Valentiners' two boys, Max + Claus., 9
    - Verso: Valentiners' two boys, Max + Claus. (Valentiner), 9-verso
    - Max and Claus Valentiner (two sons)., 10
    - Verso: Max and Claus Valentiner (two sons). Return to Valentiner, 10-verso
    - Mrs. Max Valentiner + boys in Breslau. Heine [?] Frau in kinder in Auto, Breslau 1927., 11
    - Verso: Mrs. Max Valentiner + boys in Breslau. Heine [?] Frau in kinder in Auto, Breslau 1927. Return to Valentiner, 11-verso
    - Commander Max Valentiner (cabinet card), 12
    - Verso: Commander Max Valentiner, U-38, 12-verso
    - Valentiner (cabinet card), 13
    - Valentiner, 14
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - family, circa 1880s - early 1900s; 2 (Box 1512)
    - Plowen school in 1897 (cabinet card), 1
    - Verso: Ploner Gymnasium 1897. Plowen school in 1897., 1-verso
    - in Ploen 1897 (Max and Monty) (cabinet card), 2
    - Verso: in Ploen 1897 (Max and Monty) Valentiner, 2-verso
    - Ploen 1899 At school at Ploen Max at right end. (cabinet card), 3
    - Verso: Ploen 1899 At school at Ploen Max at right end., 3-verso
    - School in Ploen Valentiner at lower right (cabinet card), 4
    - Verso: School in Ploen Valentiner at lower right. [some german?] Return to Valentiner., 4-verso
    - Mrs. Valentiner + two brothers at time she was married (mounted photograph), 5
    - Verso: Mrs. Valentiner + two brothers at time she was married, 5-verso
    - (mounted Photograph), 6
    - Mrs. Valentiner when v. first met her (15) (mounted photograph), 7
    - Verso: Mrs. Valentiner when v. first met her (15) Valentiner., 7-verso
    - Am grossen Ploener See [German for 'On Great Ploen Lake']. Schoolboy at Ploen (mounted photograph), 8
    - Verso: Am grossen Ploener See [German for 'On Great Ploen Lake']. Schoolboy at Ploen. Valentiner., 8-verso
    - As schoolboy at Ploen (mounted photograph), 9
    - Verso: As schoolboy at Ploen, 9-verso
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - U-boats, circa 1900 - 1918; 3 (Box 1512)
    - [Schiatzmeyer(?) U-157], 1
    - Verso: Schiatzmeyer(?) U-157, 1-verso
    - [SMS Moltke, Cadet training day], 2
    - Verso: SMS Moltke, Cadet training ship, 2-verso
    - [SMS Moltke, Cadet training ship], 3
    - Verso: SMS Moltke, Cadet training ship, 3-verso
    - [SMS Moltke, Cadet training ship], 4
    - Verso: SMS Moltke, Cadet training ship, 4-verso
    - [Captain of SMS Moltke in Morgader(?)], 5
    - Verso: Captain of SMS Moltke in Morgader(?), 5-verso
    - [Officers and cadets of SMS Moltke], 6
    - Verso: Officers and cadets of SMS Moltke, 6-verso
    - [Cadets from SMS Moltke training ship], 7
    - Verso: Cadets from SMS Moltke training ship, 7-verso
    - [Valentines], 8
    - Verso: Valentines, 8-verso
    - [Ship stopped by U-157], 9
    - Verso: Ship stopped by U-157 Return to Max Valentines, 9-verso
    - [Sailing ship stopped by U-157], 10
    - Verso: Sailing ship stopped by U-157], 10-verso
    - [Postcard(?)], 11
    - Verso: This is unanswered, 11-verso
    - [Crew U-157], 12
    - Verso:Crew U-157, 12-verso
    - [Lt. Wendlarat(?)], 13
    - Verso: Lt. Wendlarat(?) M138, 13-verso
    - [Boat fueled(?) in woods by Russian prisoners to escape to Denmark from Germany], 14
    - Verso: Boat fueled(?) in woods by Russian prisoners to escape to Denmark from Germany, 14-verso
    - [Valentines as cadet], 15
    - Verso: Valentines as cadet, 15-verso
    - [Als Kammandant(?)], 16
    - Verso: Als Kammandant(?), 16-verso
    - [Men in diving suits repairing part of a boat], 17
    - [Vigo Spain], 18
    - Verso: Vigo Spain, 18-verso
    - [Waterfront], 19
    - Verso: Theo Valentines, 19-verso
    - [Village of Tondern(?)], 20
    - Verso: Village of Tondern(?), 20-verso
    - [U-13 at sea(?)], 21
    - Verso: [Large paragraph written in German], 21-verso
    - [Sonderlug(?)], 22
    - Verso: Sonderlug(?), 22-verso
    - [Schwanesee(?)], 23
    - Verso: [Large paragraph written in German], 23-verso
    - [Kaiser at Kiel 1913], 24
    - Verso: Kaiser at Kiel 1913, 24-verso
    - [Admiral al(?)], 25
    - Verso: Admiral al(?), 25-verso
    - [Man indiving suit], 26
    - Verso: [Large paragraph written in German], 26-verso
    - [Leut. L.Fischer], 27
    - Verso: Lt. Com. Fischer, 27-verso
    - [In Sonderbury(?)], 28
    - Verso: In Sonderbury(?), 28-verso
    - [Corrida de toros (running of the bulls)], 29
    - [Lt. Com. Swan], 30
    - Verso: Lt. Com. Swan, 30-verso
    - [Comm. Klaus Hanson], 31
    - Verso: Comm. Klaus Hanson, lost when the U-41 was sunk, 31-verso
    - [Valentines ship in Far East], 32
    - Verso: Valentines ship in Far East, 32-verso
    - [U-16(?)], 33
    - Verso: [Large paragraph written in German], 33-verso
    - [House in Sonderburg where Val's mother and sister live], 34
    - Verso: House in Sonderburg where Val's mother and sister live, 34-verso
    - [Visit from Enver Pasha(?)], 35
    - Verso: Visit from Enver Pasha(?), 35-verso
    - [Als Kammandant(?)], 36
    - Verso: Als Kammandant(?), 36-verso
    - [Home of Valentines in Ketting], 37
    - Verso: Home of Valentines in Ketting, 37-verso
    - [U-157], 38
    - Verso: U-157, 38-verso
    - [U-Boat], 39
    - [Dic Irlandia(?) 1921], 40
    - Verso: Dic Irlandia(?) 1921, 40-verso
    - [Row Boat], 41
    - [The Irlandia (?) 1921 - Valentines trading schooner], 42
    - Verso: The Irlandia (?) 1921 - Valentines trading schooner, 42-verso
    - [Infanta Isabella de Bourbon stopped by h157], 43
    - Verso: Infanta Isabella de Bourbon stopped by h157, 43-verso
    - [Berm Firchfang auf dur Irlandia(?)], 44
    - Verso: Berm Firchfang auf dur Irlandia(?), 44-verso
    - [Loading rubber from SS Norefass], 45
    - Verso: Loading rubber from SS Norefass, 45-verso
    - [Ingemirr Rust ron hist(?)], 46
    - Verso: Ingemirr Rust ron hist(?), 46-verso
    - [Man on U-boat], 47
    - [Spanish ship], 48
    - Verso: Spanish ship, 48-verso
    - [On SS Moltke], 49
    - Verso: On SS Moltke, 49-verso
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - U-boats, circa 1900 - 1918; 4 (Box 1512)
    - [Auf dur Irlandia(?) 1921], 1
    - Verso: Auf dur Irlandia(?) 1921, 1-verso
    - [In cabin on Irlandia (?) 1921], 2
    - Verso: In cabin on Irlandia (?) 1921, 2-verso
    - [Men raising flags on deck], 3
    - Verso: Return to time: probably Feb 1917, 3-verso
    - [Deep sea divers], 4
    - [Old castle at Sonderburg], 5
    - Verso: Old castle at Sonderburg, 5-verso
    - [Sinking ship], 6
    - Verso, 6-verso
    - [U-38], 7
    - Verso: U-38, 7-verso
    - [Crew aboard ship], 8
    - [The Georgeans who were put on land at Pole on Black Sea...], 9
    - Verso: The Georgeans who were put on land at Pole on Black Sea, 9-verso
    - [Crew on a ship], 10
    - Verso: [?], 10-verso
    - [U-38 at Beirut(?)...], 11
    - Verso: U-38 at Beirut(?), 11-verso
    - [U-38 in Jaffa], 12
    - Verso: U-38 in Jaffa, 12-verso
    - [Men in a rowboat], 13
    - Verso: [?], 13-verso
    - [Men on a boat], 14
    - [Heller watching path of torpedo], 15
    - Verso: Heller watching path of torpedo, 15-verso
    - [Men on small boats being lowered from a ship], 16
    - [Ship], 17
    - [Crew on a ship], 18
    - [Sinking ship], 19
    - [Crew on a ship], 20
    - [Crew on a ship], 21
    - [U38 from top of foremast], 22
    - Verso: U38 from top of foremast, 22-verso
    - [Ships at dock(?)], 23
    - Verso: [?], 23-verso
    - [A ship being blown up], 24
    - [Sinking ship], 25
    - Verso: [?], 25-verso
    - [Sinking ship], 26
    - Verso: [?], 26-verso
    - [Sinking ship], 27
    - [Crew aboard ship], 28
    - Verso: [?], 28-verso
    - [View from a high mast(?)], 29
    - Verso: [?], 29-verso
    - [ship], 30
    - [Norwegian sailing ship], 31
    - Verso: Norwegian sailing ship, 31-verso
    - [U38 in harbour on Dalmation coast], 32
    - Verso: U38 in harbour on Dalmation coast, 32-verso
    - [Crew on ship], 33
    - [Ship], 34
    - [U38 sinking steamer], 35
    - Verso: U38 sinking steamer, 35-verso
    - [U38 at Constantinople], 36
    - Verso: U38 at Constantinople, 36-verso
    - [Sinking ship], 37
    - [U-38 Wendlandt(right) travelers on watch(?)], 38
    - Verso: U-38 Wendlandt(right) travelers on watch(?), 38-verso
    - [View from ship], 39
    - Verso: [?], 39-verso
    - [Ship], 40
    - [Ship going up in smoke], 41
    - [U-38], 42
    - Verso: U-38, 42-verso
    - [U-38 in bad weather], 43
    - Verso: U-38 bad weather, 43-verso
    - [Dingi(?) of U-38 goes over to stopped ship], 44
    - Verso: Dingi(?) of U-38 goes over to stopped ship, 44-verso
    - [Ship], 45
    - [Ship going up in smoke], 46
    - [Sinking ship], 47
    - [Sinking ship], 48
    - [U38 in tow to Madeira], 49
    - Verso: U38 in tow to Madeira, 49-verso
    - [Ship], 50
    - [Sinking ship], 51
    - [Crew on a ship], 52
    - [Sinking ship(?)], 53
    - Verso: [?], 53-verso
    - [Two crew members], 54
    - [Small rowboat alongside ship], 55
    - Verso: [?], 55-verso
    - [U-boat(?)], 56
    - [Zeppelin in the sky], 57
    - [U-boat(?)], 58
    - [Ship going up in smoke], 59
    - [View of ship firing off torpedo(?)], 60
    - [U-boat(?)], 61
    - [Man in diving suit(?)], 62
    - [Man in diving suit(?)], 62
    - [U157 taking rubber from Norefass(?)], 63
    - Verso: U157 taking rubber from Norefass(?), 63-verso
    - [Auf dur Bruske rom Norefass(?)], 64
    - Verso: Auf dur Bruske rom Norefass(?), 64-verso
    - [Crew aboard ship], 65
    - Verso: [?], 65-verso
    - [U157 entfermungs messer(?)], 66
    - Verso: U157 entfermungs messer(?), 66-verso
    - [Crew aboard ship], 67
    - Verso: [?], 67-verso
    - [Kommandant und arrt(?) U157], 68
    - Verso: Kommandant und arrt(?) U157, 68-verso
    - [Members of the crew], 69
    - Verso: [?], 69-verso
    - [Crew aboard the ship], 70
    - Verso: [U157 (?)], 70-verso
    - [Ochich (?) at left, on Norefass U157], 71
    - Verso: Ochich (?) at left, on Norefass U157, 71-verso
    - [Ingmierr Rust mit Taush - retter auf (?) U157], 72
    - Verso: Ingmierr Rust mit Taush - retter auf (?) U157, 72-verso
    - [Junger Schweinsfrash(?) U157], 73
    - Verso: Junger Schweinsfrash(?) U157, 73-verso
    - [U-157], 74
    - Verso: U-157, 74-verso
    - [Steward and sailors U-157], 75
    - Verso: Steward and sailors U-157, 75-verso
    - [U-157], 76
    - Verso: U-157, 76-verso
    - [Auf dur Norefass U-157], 77
    - Verso: Auf dur Norefass U-157, 77-verso
    - [Instrument for getting gun range, U-157], 78
    - Verso: Instrument for getting gun range, U-157, 78-verso
    - [Der Kapitan rom Norefass at left and steward, U-157], 79
    - Verso: Der Kapitan rom Norefass at left and steward, U-157, 79-verso
    - [On Vulcan(?) - Valentines and Dr. Valentine], 80
    - Verso: On Vulcan(?) - Valentines and Dr. Valentine, 80-verso
    - [SMS Vulkan], 81
    - Verso: SMS Vulkan, 81-verso
    - [small monkey], 82
    - Verso: Hubu(?), 82-verso
    - [small monkey], 83
    - Verso: der affe hubu(?), 83-verso
    - [U-157], 84
    - Verso: U-157, 84-verso
    - [Small monkey and bird], 85
    - Verso: U-157, 85-verso
    - [Men next to boat on the dock], 86
    - Verso: [?], 86-verso
    - [Men next to boat on the dock], 87
    - Verso: [?], 87-verso
    - [Dog and monkey on boat], 88
    - Verso: der affe hubu und terrier bambu (?), 88-verso
    - [Ship], 89
    - Verso: Kapitan Gausser ber der Insel Ferra (?), 89-verso
    - [Sailboat], 90
    - Verso: Kanarikher Fischer (?), 90-verso
    - [Ship at sea], 91
    - [U-157], 92
    - Verso: U-157, 92-verso
    - [Deep sea diver], 93
    - Verso: [?], 93-verso
    - [Norefass], 94
    - Verso: Norefass, 94-verso
    - [A bull(?) and a dog aboard a ship], 95
    - Verso: U-157, 95-verso
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - U-boats, circa 1900 - 1918; 5 (Box 1512)
    - Note: #34, #35 [two German names], 1
    - [Ship at sea], 2
    - [Man], 3
    - Note: [illegible German], 4
    - Note: #45 [illegible German name], 5
    - [View from aboard a ship, (U-20?)], 6
    - Note: #10 deck of U-20; #11 Rubbler [?], 7
    - [Sinking ship], 8
    - [U-boat going underwater], 9
    - [Crew aboard the ship], 10
    - Note: #12 a list and a plunge[?]; #13 [illegible], 11
    - [Dog aboard a ship], 12
    - [Two small rowboats alongside a ship], 13
    - Note: #64 [?] alongside O-35; #65 Maria de [?] U-20, 14
    - [Sailboat alongside a ship], 15
    - [Crew aboard a ship], 16
    - Note: #6 [?] English captains, 17
    - [View of a sailboat at sea], 18
    - Note: #5 Norwegian 3500 ton just before being sunk by U-117, 19
    - [Sinking ship], 20
    - Note: #42 English ship [?], 21
    - [Crew member holding a dog], 22
    - Note: #58, 23
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - U-boats, circa 1900 - 1918; 6 (Box 1512)
    - [A German U-boat], 1
    - Verso: A German U-boat, 1-verso
    - [A U-boat holding up an enemy trade steamer], 2
    - Verso: A U-boat holding up an enemy trade steamer, 2-verso
    - [Old baptismal font found in yard of Valentines father], 3
    - Verso: Old baptismal font found in yard of Valentines father, now in Sonderburg museum, 3-verso
    - [Officers on SMS Moltke, training ship], 4
    - Verso: Officers on SMS Moltke, training ship, 4-verso
    - [Naval officer (?)], 5
    - Verso: U38 Black Sea Story, 5-verso
    - [Ship at sea], 6
    - [Ship at sea], 7
    - [From from a ship at sea], 8
    - Verso: Part 8 Reel 2 (end of second reel), 8-verso
    - [Cadets in Mogador (?) Africa], 9
    - Verso: Cadets in Mogador (?) Africa, 9-verso
    - [This is the "Vulcan" U-boat rescue ship], 10
    - Verso: This is the "Vulcan" U-boat rescue ship, 10-verso
    - [Danger signal], 11
    - Verso: These little animals are the first give the warning of dreaded danger..., 11-verso
    - [Crew on the lookout of a ship], 12
    - Verso: Outside of the mine line, the neutral Spanish steamer Asuarca comes in right, 12-verso
    - [Crew aboard a ship], 13
    - [The lookout after a "sub"], 14
    - Verso: The lookout after a "sub", 14-verso
    - ["Victims of the Submarine" painting], 15
    - Verso: "Victims of the Submarine" painting, artist: Richard V. Schulter (?), 15-verso
    - ["History of the World War" painting], 16
    - Verso: "History of the World War" painting, by Francis A. March, 16-verso
    - ["The Survivors" drawing], 17
    - Verso: "The Survivors" drawing by Louis Raemahors (?), 17-verso
    - [U-35 German Submarine], 18
    - Verso: U-35 German Submarine (1917) in heavy waters, 18-verso
    - [Ship beingblown up (?)], 19
    - [Drawing of a submarine underwater], 20
    - [Boat in a body of water at Sonderburg], 21
    - Verso: [?], 21-verso
    - [In Sonderburg museum, picture of Valentines], 22
    - Verso: In Sonderburg museum, picture of Valentines, 22-verso
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - U-boats, circa 1900 - 1918; 7 (Box 1512)
    - [An American sailing ship, the "Hallie Dunn"], 1
    - Verso: An American sailing ship, the "Hallie Dunn", sunk in 1918, the crew is deserting the ship, 1-verso
    - [U-35], 2
    - Verso: U-35, 2-verso
    - [Sailing vessel sunk by the "Miss Morris," English...], 3
    - Verso: Sailing vessel sunk by the "Miss Morris," English, 3-verso
    - [Sailing vessel sunk by the "Miss Morris," English...], 4
    - Verso: Sailing vessel sunk by the "Miss Morris," English, 4-verso
    - [Cleaning of deck gun of U-35], 5
    - Verso: Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather, 5-verso
    - [The ship's bout (of the armed English steamer "Parkgate")...], 6
    - Verso: The ship's bout (of the armed English steamer "Parkgate"), 6-verso
    - [Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather], 7
    - Verso: Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather, 7-verso
  - Submarines: Georg Ritter von Trapp, undated; 8 (Box 1512)
    - Georg Ritter von Trapp [View of Salzburg, where Comm. Von Trapp lives], 1
    - Verso: View of Salzburg, where Comm. Von Trapp live, 1-verso
    - [Georg (?) Ritter von Trapp], 2
    - Verso: Georg (?) Ritter von Trapp, Commander of U5 and U14, Austrian submarines, 2-verso